The greatest love story you have never gnome.
Gnomeo & Juliet is a animation, family film directed by Kelly Asbury.
A version of Shakespeare's play, set in the world of
warring indoor and outdoor gnomes.
Garden gnomes Gnomeo and Juliet have as many obstacles to overcome as their quasi
namesakes when they are caught up in a feud between neighbors.
But with plastic pink flamingos and lawnmower races in the mix,
can this young couple find lasting happiness?
Gnomeo (voice), played by James McAvoy.
Juliet (voice), played by Emily Blunt.
Lord Redbrick (voice), played by Michael Caine.
Lady Bluebury (voice), played by Maggie Smith.
Lady Montague (voice), played by Julie Walters.
Featherstone (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Gnomeo & Juliet is a 2011 animated romantic
comedy film directed by Kelly Asbury.
It is loosely based on the play Romeo and Juliet, and features the voices of James McAvoy, Emily Blunt, Michael Caine, Maggie Smith, Jason Statham, Patrick
Stewart, Ashley Jensen, Stephen Merchant, Matt Lucas, Jim Cummings, Julie Walters, Richard Wilson, Ozzy Osbourne, Dolly Parton, and Hulk Hogan.
The story follows Gnomeo and Juliet, a pair of garden gnomes who fall in love, but due to the feud between
their respective families, they must find a way to keep their blossoming romance a secret.
Gnomeo & Juliet premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood on
January 23, 2011, and was theatrically released on February 11.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
$193 million on a $36 million budget.
It received nominations for four Annie Awards.
The song "Hello Hello" by Elton John and Lady Gaga was nominated for the Golden Globe award,
the Satellite Award, and the Critics' Choice Award for Best Original Song.
A sequel, Sherlock Gnomes, was released in 2018.
The film explores themes of garden, villain, forbidden
love, kiss, based on play or musical.